Bocchi-chan!
Sorry, sorry!
Didn't mean to startle you.
I-It's okay.
Cola, right?
Wh-Wh-What? Yes?
Here!
Th-Thank you.
Sorry if I forced you to go along with this.
I mean, you kind of just got roped into
joining Kessoku Band from the start, right?
I remember you saying...
you'd been wanting
to be part of a band,
but I never actually asked you what
kind of band you wanted to be in,
or what your reasons were
for playing in this band now.
Ah. I broke 30,000 subscribers.
Hey, that's right.
The online world is where I belong.
I practiced six hours every day, so I could
learn how to play in front of people...
The result?
Middle school ended, and I
never played a single note for them!
Congrats on Graduating!
I never performed once...
98th Annual Graduation Ceremony
At the culture festival!
I never put together...
The members for a band!
And I never made a single friend...
In three whole years!
Now, in high school...
Graduation
Yokohama Genseiryo Middle School
I gotta form a band or die trying!
But despite my vow, it's been a whole month
since high school started,
and yet my heart remains
grounded in the guitar,
little better than a shut-in...
Lyrics and music by me.
From the closet with love.
But before I cause neighborhood problems
playing my crummy original song late at night,
Drag & Drop to Upload Video
Choose File
Upload Video
I've gotta upload a cover
I did of a popular band.
Uploading...
It's been a pretty long time
since I started uploading myself
playing under the name "guitarhero"
on my dad's advice, but...
Wow, my latest video already
has so many comments.
[Guitar] Acid "Spring Snow" [Gave it a try]
Views                                                        Dislike
Sorry I can't upload very often nowadays!
There's just so much going on at high school!
Next time I'll try a song I do all the time
with my friends at karaoke!
[Guitar] Acid "Spring Snow" [Gave it a try]
Views                                                        Dislike
Sorry I can't upload very often nowadays!
There's just so much going on at high school!
Next time I'll try a song I do all the time
with my friends at karaoke!
[Guitar] Acid "Spring Snow" [Gave it a try]
Views                                                        Dislike
Sorry I can't upload very often nowadays!
There's just so much going on at high school!
Next time I'll try a song I do all the time
with my friends at karaoke!
10 comments                 Sort
Add Public Comment
Pyonkichi  5 Minutes Ago
You're so good! Are you a pro by any chance? :D
Sam03  30 Minutes Ago
You rocked the chorus, love it
I've been racking up the views lately, too,
and people are telling me I'm good...
Yeah, maybe it's okay
if I can't handle real life!
There are tons of people
cheering for me online!
Sam03  30 Minutes Ago
You rocked the chorus, love it
Nekomi  5 Minutes Ago
I listen to this every day!
I just started playing guitar myself and I'm so in awe!
Can't wait for the next one!
The internet is filled with socially
anxious introverts just like me!
Deyon  1 hour ago
2:17 this part rocks
Johnson 1 hour ago
Gomachin  1 hour ago
What pedals are you using?
Kaopin  1 hour ago
I formed a band and played this for our culture festival!
The whole school went crazy for it!
"I formed a band and played this for our cul—"
I put the effort in, okay?
I brought CDs to school
and set them on my desk.
Talk to me!
I bought band merch and showed it off.
I put in song requests at lunch...
This next song is a request
from Gotoh-san in Class 2-A.
I'm gonna...
...for the death metal song
I'd been obsessed with lately.
I'm gonna...
I'm gonna crush your skuuull!!!
Not the flashbacks!
Begone! Begone, filthy memories!
Gomachin  1 hour ago
What pedals are you using?
Kaopin  1 hour ago
I formed a band and played this
for our culture festival!
The whole school went crazy for it!
I wish I could perform live...
Gomachin  1 hour ago
What pedals are you using?
Kaopin  1 hour ago
I formed a band and played this
for our culture festival!
The whole school went crazy for it!
Replies
OZAKI  30 minutes ago
I played it with my band club too!
Taku  5 minutes ago
Lucky! Not sure if there's anyone at
my high school that plays guitar...
Taku  5 minutes ago
Lucky! Not sure if there's anyone at
my high school that plays guitar...
That...
That could work!
Sleep Pipe
I look... I look so cool!
I'm already a total rocker chick!
I look like a real somebody!
The people can't look away!
Someone's just gotta talk to me now!
I'm gonna be all over this
year's culture festival!
So you could see the corgi's butt...
Do we move rooms next period?
Science Room B.
Hey, wanna karaoke after this?
Great idea!
You sure?
Wonder what I should sing...
Sorta makes me not wanna go back to school...
Guitar!
That's a guitar, right?
Do you play?!
Hello?
I-I haven't talked to anyone
in so long... My voice!
Hey, sorry to ambush you.
I'm Nijika Ijichi, second-year
at Shimo-Kitazawa High.
Hitori Gotoh. Shuka High. First-year.
So tell me, Hitori-chan...
Right to first names, are we?!
How good are you at guitar?
Pretty decent, I guess...
Really?!
Say, I'm in kind of a fix here...
If you can't do it, that's okay, but...
It's really okay, but I'm in a real fix...
There's nothing okay about her!
Okay, I'll come right out with it!
Please, will you play second
guitar for my band for today?!
Band?
We've got a concert coming up,
and our guitarist just split!
The song's not too hard!
You'll pick it up right away!
A concert?! Right now?!
Please! Please!
Thanks! Let's head to the club!
I haven't even said anything yet!
Good morning!
My first club...
It's so dark... So stuffy...
I-It's so soothing!
You okay, Hitori-chan?
I'm home!
No, you're not!
Could we ask the PA to record again?
That's the band that's playing today.
I thought bands would be intimidating,
They might be a little older than us?
but they're all indoorsy, shy introverts!
After they're done, we'll rehearse too.
They're just like me!
That there's the PA.
Do not spill drinks on equipment!
Good morning.
Please forgive my arrogance!
What's wrong now?!
You're finally back.
Ryo!
This is Hitori Gotoh. Hitori-chan!
I met her in the park by miraculous
happenstance! She's a guitarist!
Oh?
Scary! Is she glaring at me?
This is Ryo Yamada. She plays bass.
I-I'm Hitori Gotoh! I'm so very sorry!
Hang on!
Y-You're okay!
Ryo's just not the expressive type.
Feel free to call her weird! She likes it!
I don't, actually.
Seemed like she did...
By the way, about the manager...
She told you to practice until it was time,
but instead you snuck out of the club,
so she got so mad she went out shopping.
N-No way!
Let's be in the studio before she comes back!
You too, Hitori-chan!
C'mon!
R-Right!
Here's today's set list and score.
Wh-Where are the other band members?
This is everyone!
We'll be doing all instrumentals this time.
Right. I can handle this song.
Though without any vocals, the playing's
gotta be all that much better...
But I'm supposedly good at guitar. I can do this.
I think I can do this!
Gorilla?
Maybe they'll be blown away by my playing!
I mean, I get pretty good...
pretty decent reactions online.
Let's take it right from the top.
It's your first time,
so we'll run through slow,
I even have 30,000 subscribers!
then we can speed it up
as you get used to it.
Yeah, let's do this!
Okay, let's go!
You suck!
H-How can I suck?
Ah, I'm kidding!
I'm guitarhero!
Well, not totally kidding, but...
Ah, I'm sorry!
I've got 30,000 subscribers!
Allow me to explain!
Guitar Man's
Easy-to-Learn
Hitori Classes
In a band, it's super important to be in
sync with your fellow live performers!
But Hitori has social anxiety
and can't make eye contact,
and she'll be inclined to
rush ahead of the others!
God
Social Butterfly
Normal Person
Water Flea
Hitori
She might be an awesome solo player,
but when in a band, she's sub-water-flea
level, the worst there is!
Hello. I'm Plankton Gotoh.
She sounds like an unfunny comedian!
And thus, Hitori Gotoh turned to dust,
and never picked up a guitar again.
BOCCHI THE ROCK!
THE                               END
Water Flea                Hitori Gotoh
Drummer                  Nijika Ijichi
Bassist                       Ryo Yamada
Guitar Man              As Himself
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait!
Come out, please!
The show's about to start!
I c-c-can't do it!
It's not your fault!
We just came together today!
It's not like I'm very good either.
I'm very good.
Just look at me, okay!
Stay here in reality!
It isn't like I could
do the intro or anything...
I-I could offer up my life
to put on a harakiri show!
Th-They'll at least remember
the name of the band, right?
Sorry I sucked!
That's a little too rock!
Sorry.
But...
We can't force her.
You're right.
Sorry to push you so hard.
No, actually...
I r-really was happy you reached out to me.
I've wanted to be in a band for so long...
B-But I couldn't get the people together...
So I just upload covers
to the internet instead.
What do you usually play?
M-Mostly songs by popular bands
from the last few years,
so I could play them right away
once the band got together...
That's awesome!
It's not.
It's the reason I'm the way I am now.
Being in a band with other people
was a pipe dream after all.
Covering all popular songs?
She sounds like guitarhero-san!
Have you heard of her?
She's probably about our age, I think...
guitarhero...
[Guitar] Acid "Spring Snow" [Gave it a try]
Views: 1,012
Sorry I can't upload very often nowadays!
There's just so much going on at high school!
Next time I'll try a song I do all the time
with my friends at karaoke!
10 comments                                      Sort
M-Me?!
I'll send you a link if you haven't!
She's super awesome! You should hear her!
Awe... some?
She comes up in my recommendations
a lot, so I've seen her too.
She really is excellent.
Right?!
Though her naming sense is a bit cringy...
It is?!
I follow her with notifications on!
I'd love to play with her some day!
You just did, actually...
Look, what I'm getting at here
is that even awesome, popular people
are out there playing guitar,
lots and lots of them,
in places we're not even watching.
You should watch her later!
I think you'll get what I mean
if you watch the videos.
I always figured real-life people
didn't care about me at all...
You can't give up on playing in a band
just because it didn't work out today!
It's possible it's our problem, anyway...
Our problem?
Hitori-chan?
But someone this nice has been
watching me all this time,
and actually spoke to me...
She stood up.
It's the kind of miracle
most people never experience!
I can't let it go to waste!
I... I'm...
D-Do you want to perform after all?
Hitori-chan?
I know all that, rationally...
But I'm still too scared...
There's no way I can play
in front of an audience...
If you're scared,
you could play from in here.
Ripe Mangos
How you feelin' tonight, Shimo-Kita?!
She's suddenly more outgoing.
By the way, how do you
want us to introduce you?
"Hitori-chan"? Should we use your real name?
I'd... I'd rather not...
Any nicknames, then?
In middle school, they called me
"Hey" and "You there"...
I don't think those are nicknames!
I never knew anyone well enough
to get nicknames from them!
Hitori...
Hitoribocchi (all alone)...
How about Bocchi-chan?
Another tactless comment!
I'm B-B-Bocchi!
She likes it?
It's just my first ever nickname...
This is making me teary-eyed.
Oh, you haven't told me your band name yet.
It's Kessoku Band.
Kessoku Band...
Isn't that the word for "zip tie"?
It's brilliant.
It's the worst pun!
We're totally changing it!
Why? It's cute.
Y-Yes.
Band name aside, it's time to play!
Don't worry.
The key is to have fun, even if you suck!
Your feelings really come
out in your playing, see?
R-Right...
We can always work on the
skill part next time.
Yeah.
Next... time...
Okay, let's go!
Right.
They're okay with there being a next time!
Nice to meet you! We're Kessoku Band!
We'll play a bunch of
songs you probably know,
so please enjoy!
Who's that?
I hate that I can't play as
well as I usually do, but...
playing in a band with other
people is so much fun!
I've never really shone before today...
And I still don't!
This might actually be a low point for me!
Boy, I screwed up!
Your intro bombed, too.
E-Excuse me!
B-B-B...
What?
B-B-B-B-B...
Okay, you're freaking me out!
B-Before our next performance, I'm gonna get
brave enough to say hello to my classmates!
What a dramatic declaration.
Such growth...
Okay, I get it.
Sure!
Then let's have a Bocchi-chan-welcome-party-
slash-concert-post-mortem!
Actually, I'm pretty exhausted from
all this social interaction, so I'm gonna go.
Sorry. I'm sleepy.
P-Pardon me!
I'm gonna get over my social anxiety
and bring out my full guitarhero powers!
For Nijika-chan,
Ryo-san,
and Kessoku Band!
S-Sorry! Sorry!
Okay!
I hereby declare the first Kessoku Band
members' meeting... open!
Round of applause!
Clappy clappy clap clap clap!
Now, let's see...
Oh, wait. We barely know each other,
so I dunno what to talk about!
She just admitted it!
I brought this for just such an occasion.
Bungee Jumping
Nice one!
I don't think I like the looks of this...
Um...
Our first concert was instrumentals only,
but I'd like to have vocals next time.
Oh, do you?
The guitarist who ran off was
gonna be our singer, but...
Where'd she even go, anyway?
The runaway guitarist...
Maybe she's socially anxious like me.
No, there's no way!
If you're really socially anxious,
you can't even run away!
We've gotta find a new vocalist.
I can't sing for squat, myself.
Bocchi-chan, can you—
Yeah... Figured.
Um... Wh-What about Ryo-san?
Sob
If I were to serve as frontman,
I'd overwhelm the band and crush it.
Sob
Where do you get that
wellspring of confidence?
Sob
I'm so jealous.
I'd like a little of that
confidence for myself...
I know!
Let's find a vocalist and write a song!
Ryo can write the music,
and if you've got off-limits words,
Bocchi-chan, you should write the lyrics!
Me?!
Well? Great idea, huh?
The nine years of lunch breaks
I spent in school libraries...
Was it all in preparation for this moment?
So, what will you do, Nijika?
Go!
Next, talk about quotas!
Just shamelessly dodged that one, eh?
A bunch of my friends came
to yesterday's concert,
so we managed to meet our quota, but...
After that performance,
they likely won't be back.
Anyway, since we'll need tens of thousands
of yen before our next concert,
let's get jobs to cover
the quota and equipment!
Okay.
Jobs?!
That's the loudest I've ever heard you.
No.
I don't want to work. Too scary!
Society is too scary!
M-My mom was saving up for my wedding...
But you can have it.
Just... Please, no job...
Don't make us the bad guys here!
Thanks, we'll take good care of—
We're not taking it!
We can't take money that
means that much to you!
But...
I don't wanna work!
Because...
W-Welcome... Sh-Should I warm... up?
It'd totally be like that...
Not this cashier who can't even make eye contact lmaoooooooooooooo
W-Welcome... Sh-Should I warm... up?
And then that...
Breaking
Defendant Hitori Gotoh's First Trial
For the crime of creeping out the customers,
we seek the death penalty!
Okay, here comes the ruling...
Death!
And then that!
...cchi-chan.
Bocchi-chan.
Bocchi-chan!
You weren't listening, were you?
S-Sorry!
Wh-What were you saying?
You should work here with us.
Here?
What?!
You won't have to be scared
if you're with me and Ryo!
Talk about Quotas
It's a homey and harmonious place to work.
We can serve drinks, and clean,
and see all kinds of bands!
Don't wanna work... Don't wanna work...
Well? What do you think?
Say no, girl!
Say no!
You have to say no!
I'll dwu mwy bwest...
Really? Thanks so much!
Good work today.
Take care getting home.
Bye-bye.
Th-Thank you for having me.
Not leaving, Ryo?
Staying a little while first.
Bocchi-chan!
Y-Yes?!
See you later!
Y-Yes, s-s-s-see you tomorrow!
Thank you for the meal.
A quiet place like this
is just perfect for lunch.
I'm glad I found a nice spot.
It's awkward eating all alone
in the classroom.
And once I become a popular guitarist,
I'll go on Oto-Station and say...
What were you like in high school?
I didn't have any friends back then.
I often ate lunch in a dark corner
filled with desks and janitorial supplies.
I can awe people with how much
I've changed! Y'know how it is...
Karaoke was so much fun the other day!
People!
Kita-chan's such a great singer.
I heard she played guitar in a band before she quit.
Kids, don't try this at home!
Wow! Now that's musical talent!
Band?
Come to think of it, Nijika-chan was talking
about wanting a new guitar-slash-vocalist...
But the thought of going up
to a total stranger...
Kita-chan!
Heya!
I'm super sorry, but I have
a huge favor to ask...
What kind of girl is she?
What is it?
Would you mind pitching in at
our basketball game next week?
She's pretty!
Hey, sure thing!
She's super nice!
Kids, don't try this at home!
Maybe I'll land a three-pointer!
She's pretty, and athletic, and popular,
Awesome! Thanks!
and she plays the guitar...
I'm supposed to issue an
invitation to someone like her?!
I worked up the courage
to arrive at her classroom,
but my mental fortitude lags behind...
You're Gotoh-san from Class 2, right?
Are you looking for someone in here?
S-Say it, Hitori!
Band Is Looking For
A Guitar/Vocalist
"My band is looking for a guitar-slash-
vocalist. Would you be interested?"
Ba! Gui! Vo!
Ba
Gui
Vo
She became a human beatbox!
Er...
Bam-chika-boom-chika...
bam-chika-boom-chika...
I... I'm so sorry!
W-Wait!
Begone, memories...
That was awesome!
K-Kita-san?!
How long have you...
I got so worried when you ran off like that,
but that was incredible!
You're amazing at guitar, Gotoh-san!
That song you were playing
had me totally enraptured!
She's saying nice things about me!
What a nice person!
Are you in a band?
K-Kind of...
Hey, can you play other stuff? I wanna hear!
Kit-aura
The extrovert aura... It's so powerful,
I can't look straight at her!
Oh, and you were trying to talk
to someone earlier, right?
Th-This is my chance to invite her!
W-Well, our band is actually
looking for a guitar-slash-vocalist,
and I heard you played guitar, so...
Oh, so that's why.
H-Huh?
I'm sorry, Gotoh-san.
I can't join your band.
O-Oh, but...
I'm kind of a nerd, but the others are cool!
Oh, it's not a problem with you or anything.
They're holding a barbecue next weekend!
Meat!
They host a sports meet every six months!
They party in limousines after every gig!
This is the life!
They do so much cool stuff!
I don't want a band that parties that hard...
And... And...
The truth is, I can't
actually play guitar at all.
I was in another band not long ago.
I lied when I joined because
I wanted to get close to my senpai.
But the whole thing was just
beyond me, so I ran away.
Beyond you?
Yeah.
There's more to playing than just
this strum-strum stuff, right?
I'd figured this wooden stick part
was just for decoration!
It's way too hard for someone
to learn on their own.
"Major chords"? "Minor"?
What is this, baseball?
Her non-comprehension
is on a whole other level!
Did someone teach you to play, Gotoh-san?
N-No, I mostly taught myself...
What?! Really? That's awesome!
It's not that great...
I know! Will you teach me to play, Gotoh-san?
You can be my teacher!
You're so brilliant, I just know
you'll get me through it!
Oh, shucks...
I want to learn to play properly,
go back to my old band, and apologize!
So, when can you teach me?
After class, maybe?
I-I've got a job at a club after class...
Then after work, maybe?!
Is there a studio next door?
We can do it there!
Oh... Oh...
V-Very well.
Really? Thanks!
Why am I so stupid?! Say no, girl!
Can we start right away?
C-Certainly...
Crap, crap, crap, crap, crap!
I've gotta get the girls
to act like party people!
It's from Bocchi-chan.
I'm sorry!
Please come to work today blaring EDM and
dancing around with energy drinks on hand!
What in the world?
Beats me.
Oh... You work in Shimo-Kitazawa?
Y-You've been?
My last band was in Shimo-Kita,
and its members lived in the area, so...
R-Really?
Hang on!
You can't walk behind me!
I don't know the way!
I'm sorry. I'm still not
used to being here...
I'm so embarrassed!
I'm the one embarrassed here!
W-We're almost there.
It's a place called Starry.
Nijika-chan and Ryo-san
will already be there...
I'm sorry. I can't go.
How come?
I'm sorry.
I can't tell you why,
but that's the one place I can't go!
And you can never tell those people I was h—
Bocchi-chan!
Your instructions were super weird,
but I bought energy drinks like you asked!
The runaway guitarist!
So you couldn't play guitar, Kita-chan?
Nope.
And that's why you always ditched practice?
Yeah...
Poor Kita-san seems so uncomfortable...
I-If only I could think of
something nice to say.
We were worried when we didn't hear from you.
Ryo-san, so smooth!
Senpai!
I assumed you were dead, so I've been
lighting incense for you every day.
RIP.
That's a pretty wild assumption...
Um... You aren't angry?
I sorta blame ourselves
for not catching on sooner.
Besides...
We managed to work it out anyway!
S-Still, I feel too awful!
Please, let me make it up to you!
I'm not sure how...
How about you help out today at the club?
It's gonna be a busy night.
Th-That can't be enough...
No, that'd be a huge help!
Please join us!
So, go over there and get changed.
Changed?
She's pretty darn good for a fill-in worker.
Yeah, Kita-chan knows what she's doing!
Sh-She really does!
She'll give me extra time to slack off.
I'll take it out of your pay.
500 yen for a drink ticket!
What band did you come to see today?
Take a flyer, if you like!
Say, not bad at all!
I love interacting with people!
Ryo always handles reception,
but her dead eyes are kind of a problem...
And her poker face can be scary.
Ryo-senpai looks fine just the way she is!
Trash
Recyclables
Kita Kita
Bocchi. What are you doing down there?
Losing my identity.
Bocchi-chan! Bocchi-chan!
Teach Kita-chan how to do the drinks!
R-Right!
Now's my chance to restore my good name!
I can't do it!
I get nervous when I'm being watched!
Sploosh
Splooosh
Sploooosh
Splooooosh
Sploooooosh
You okay?
I think I get the idea,
so you can rest a while.
Please forgive my arrogance...
I'm just glad you
weren't seriously hurt.
Th-Thank yo...
What?
Her fingertips...
Kessoku Band
Now Recruiting Guitar/Vocalist
Even newbies can come and learn!
Please!!
Please contact STARRY staff
Here's your cola!
Um, so the senpai you
wanted to get closer to...
Yeah.
It's Ryo-senpai.
Here ya go.
Unlike you, I have very impure motives.
I saw Senpai playing on the street,
and fell head-over-heels for her.
I followed Ryo-san's activities for a while,
and she dropped out of her
last band pretty suddenly.
H-Huh...
Then I found out she was
recruiting for Kessoku Band,
and without thinking, I said I'd do it.
S-Such initiative! Extroversion abounds!
A band is like your second family, you know?
Family?
Yeah, you spend more time with them
than with your actual family,
and you're all chasing the same dream...
It's a mysterious relationship,
closer than friends or significant others.
I've never done clubs or anything similar,
so I've always wanted to be part of that.
I get you.
I always wanted it too...
Yes... I wanted to join Kessoku Band
and become Senpai's girl!
So much deeper and more
intimate than friendship!
Wait. Is Kita-san kind of not-okay?
But that's all the more reason
I can't join the band now.
I flaked out once already.
I'm too irresponsible.
I don't deserve to be in the band.
Tickets go on sale at 5 pm
Okay, good work, all. Feel free to head home.
Thanks for having us!
Thank you for having us...
Thanks for everything today.
Good luck with your band!
I'll keep rooting for you!
Goodbye!
H-Hey...
Bocchi-chan?!
Are you all right, Gotoh-san?
You're not still worried about me, are you?
I'm sorry.
Like I said before,
I can't join Kessoku Band.
I can't play guitar,
and I already flaked out once...
I... I... I...
I also ran away before the concert.
I hid in a trash can, and...
A-A-And also...
Let's get you up, Bocchi-chan.
One, two...
Here we go!
K-Kita-san, your left hand...
Y-You had calluses on your fingertips.
I... I th-think...
You'd have to be practicing
the guitar pretty hard for that.
Y-Yeah!
Kita-chan, we'd love to have you
rocking out with us in Kessoku Band!
Why would you let me...
Because if you hadn't flaked out,
we'd never have met Bocchi-chan!
Y-Yeah!
I've always wanted to have a band,
so I get how it feels intimidating
and aspirational at the same time.
S-So do I!
S-Sorry. That came out
louder than I expected.
You'd be happy to have her too, right, Ryo?
I'll only have to pay one-quarter
of the studio and quota fees.
Be a little less honest, would you?
I can be part of Senpai's quota!
So much for that healthy
moving-on thing, I guess...
But I still can't play the guitar...
That's okay!
Bocchi-chan will teach you!
Eh?
Yeah, yeah.
Ehh?
You will?
Y-Yes!
I can't exactly turn her down now!
Thank you.
I'll work really hard to
play guitar in Kessoku Band!
Oh, but you should probably give up
that party lifestyle of yours...
You're dancing like mad
every night, right?
Where'd you hear that?!
Well, I gotta head out now...
Bocchi-chan, don't go!
You're today's MVP!
You're the reason we're back together.
Thank you, Gotoh-san!
Praise me   Praise me   Praise me   Praise me   Praise me   Praise me   Praise me   Praise me   Praise me   Praise me   Praise me   Praise me   Praise me   Praise me   Praise me   Praise me   Praise me   Praise me   Praise me
Gosh, well, it was nothing,
really, honestly...
It obviously wasn't nothing for you.
Gotoh-san wears her heart on her sleeve.
But I practiced for so long, and yet
I never really learned how to play guitar.
It just made this quiet 'bum-bum' sound.
Y-You're sure it wasn't a bass?
Hey, I'm not that ignorant!
A bass has four strings, right?
See? It's got the full six strings!
S-Some do have six strings...
That's a six-string bass.
K-Kita-san!
It cost me two years'
advance allowance from my dad,
not to mention my New Year's money...
Kita-chan!
No more!
I hereby quit the guitar!
What? Are we breaking up already?
Is this one defective too?
Did I get another bass?
N-No, that's definitely a guitar...
I'm sorry I whine so much.
I know you're giving up your time after
class and during lunch to teach me...
H-Hey, it's not...
With Ryo-senpai lending me this guitar,
and everyone helping... I have to do my best.
B-But I really am glad... that Ryo-san
b-bought that bass off of you...
Yeah.
But when she gave me the money...
This is the last of my money,
so I'll be eating weeds from now on.
That was a joke, right?
She might have been serious!
Ryo-senpai! Hello...
You guys're here early.
Sh-She really is eating weeds!
Senpai's so wild!
How can we be
more band-like?
But Kita-chan looks cute in any pic we take!
Aw, no I don't!
Sure you do!
It's almost like you know what you're doing.
Oh, I guess it's because I upload pics
to Issta all the time!
See?
That's our Minister of Social Media!
Bocchi-chan's dying!
What's wrong, Gotoh-san? Stay with us!
Oh, no! She's flopping around like a fish!
I've never taken pictures
with friends before.
What do I do? Please, wake up!
Since... I never had friends before.
The only pictures I've taken
that weren't with family
were class pictures.
With those as my only proof of existence
for the past fifteen years...
Look at Bocchi-chan's weird face!
I wonder if there are any other
high school girls like me still around?
Perhaps I've become a rare species,
on par with the tsuchinoko?
I am... I am the tsuchinoko
of Shimo-Kitazawa.
Gotoh-san's saying the strangest things!
Nah, this is normal for her.
Noko-noko. Noko-noko.
Bocchi-chan, why don't you
start your own Isstagram?
What do you think, Minister?
Totally!
Let's become friends!
If we're going to be a band,
we should really have
individual member accounts!
Gotoh-san?!
If I were to get an account...
Someone with self-esteem so bad
she's already trying to form a band
to get popular despite
total social ineptitude...
If s-someone like me were to
start an account like that...
You would witness the birth of...
The attention-whore monster!
Like my posts!
You okay?
Nothing's really hitting the spot...
Hey, what about a jump pic?
Jump pic?
It's really photogenic, and it could
bring out everyone's personality!
Great idea! You're a genius, Kita-chan!
A wise man once said,
any anime where they jump in
the OP is a god-tier anime.
Would jumping in our ProPho
thus make us a god-tier band?
Where is she getting that from?
I'm not sure I followed your logic there...
But let's give it a try!
Awesome! It's got the band feel
and the seishun thing going!
Do you think I could get
a copy of that picture?
M-Me too!
Yeah, we're feeling band-like now!
I feel like we're one step closer
to becoming a popular band!
R-Right!
Kessoku Band is getting started for real!
Okay!
We'll have our concert in summer (TBD),
our demo CD sale (TBD),
our first album release in winter (TBD),
and become Shimo-Kitazawa's own
good vibes-iest vibes-band!
Sounds like there's a lot
still to be decided!
Anyway, thanks for coming today!
Dismissed!
Lyrics
She has a more important job:
writing lyrics for our original song!
We settled on it before, remember?
Ryo would write the music,
and you'd write the lyrics!
If you've got off-limits words,
Bocchi-chan, you should write the lyrics!
write the lyrics!
Wow! I can't wait to hear
your song, Ryo-senpai.
Have you written it already?
No.
I'll do it once I get inspiration.
I just can't wait!
Go for it, Ryo!
And Minister of Lyrics!
R-Right...
Gotoh-san, it's so cool that
you took on such a tough job!
C-Cool?!
W-Well, I can write lyrics
like nobody's business!
It's the super-easiest thing ever!
You get carried away so easily, Gotoh-san.
One Week Later
I couldn't think of anything!
Shake!
Change paws!
I failed to write a single lyric,
but I've perfected my signature...
Gotoh
Hitori Gotoh
Gocchi
Bocchi
This
one!
Hitori
Change, and pose!
Isn't it cool?
Why can't I get my priorities in order?!
Jimihen's amazing!
Futari!
Let's get organized.
Kita-san's gonna be singing this song.
Cheerful lyrics.
A seishun song, maybe?
Kit-aura!
I could easily write depressing lyrics,
of course...
Kit-aura!
Nobody wants that,
so I've gotta write something band-like,
with real Kit-aura!
Put yourself in the mind
of cheery person!
I'm an extrovert!
The woman who surfs in the pool at night!
The woman who claims the title Queen of Woot!
Woot! Woot! Woot!
Woot! Go! Go!
Let's get some vibes up in here!
Tequila shots in the house!
No! That's not a cheery person,
it's just a party animal!
No Peeking
Okay, no seishun songs.
Let's try a song of encouragement.
I personally find status-quo-affirming
lyrics annoyingly irresponsible, but...
we're all here
sending you
Your dreams will come true
Believe in yourself
The more time that passes,
Lyrics
the higher the lyrics bar seems to rise.
I-If I show them this and
they're mean to me...
O-Or worse, if they're
obviously humoring me, I...
M-Maybe I should show it to
someone and see how they react.
Ryo-san, maybe.
I don't think Ryo-san would ever humor me.
Ryo
a
It's a pleasure to make contact with you
This is Bocchi speaking
If you happen to still be in Shimo-Kita,
do you think you might be able to
consider having a look at my lyrics?
Read
She already read it!
I'm here, come by
Th-This is awkward.
Come to think of it, I've never
been alone with Ryo-san before.
I don't even know much about her.
F-For that matter, why hasn't
she talked to me yet?
That was delicious.
She finished eating!
What do I do? Should I initiate?
But...
That photo shoot sure was fun, huh?!
Not really.
That could be the result!
Just show me the lyrics.
Oh, right.
Thank you.
No problem. Let's see.
Are you personally satisfied
with these lyrics, Bocchi?
Oh, w-well...
I figured we should do something
really "hit band"-like...
Can't do it anymore
You say as you give up on moving forward
On a road that seems to go on forever
It feels like you'll never arrive anywhere
And that's got you worried, doesn't it?
But hey now, listen up
Don't forget you're not alone, that we're all here
We're sending you this cheer just as your heart's about to break
Your dreams will come true
Don't give up until the very end!
Believe in yourself the way you are
Believe in yourself and get walking again!
Glory awaits you ahead, I know it
For everyone around the world trying hard, Go for it!
Did I ever tell you?
I was in another band a long time ago.
Their lyrics were awkward,
but I liked how honest they were.
But, desperate for sales, they started
going in a more commercial direction.
I hated that. That's why I quit.
We had a little fight about it at the time.
And just as I was feeling sick
of the whole band thing...
Hey.
If you've got time,
will you play bass for me?
Why?
Because I love the way you play!
When Nijika said that to me, I decided
to give playing in a band another try.
Abandoning your uniqueness
is equivalent to dying.
Ryo-san?
So don't write generic lyrics
based on other concerns.
Write what you want to write.
B-But if I do that, I'll write bitter,
social-outcast lyrics—
Bringing a wide variety of individuals
together into one sound...
That's the color that Kessoku Band will have.
Oh, Ryo-san...
The check...
Sorry, I'm broke. Treat me?
Wh-What?
B-But you're the one who invited me...
I just couldn't take another
day of eating weeds.
You're still doing that?!
I really am sorry.
I'll pay you back next month.
N-No need to rush...
U-Um...
I-I'm going to try my best!
Sure. Can't wait to see it.
H-Here.
Gotoh-san, are you all right? You look tired.
I'm fine.
I've just been so focused on the lyrics,
I c-completely forgot to sleep...
Wow!
Let's have a look!
I can't wait to see the
fruits of your labors!
It m-might be... too much of a downer.
It certainly is a downer.
Ryo-senpai!
But it's very Bocchi.
It might not connect with too many people,
but those it does, it'll hit deeply.
Where'd this friendship come from?!
I'm not putting you on.
But why? We just finished our original song.
Why should I care about that?
Th-This feels super awkward...
We can even pay our quota
if we don't bring in customers!
It's not about the money.
It's about your skill.
But you let us play last time.
I made an exception so you
could make a memory.
"Make a memory"?
Normally, I'd make you play first to apply.
You know that, right?
Yeah, but...
Sorry, but I can't have a repeat
of that awful May performance.
Can't have a repeat...
You mean we...
Just stick with it as a hobby or something.
You got more to say?
You can't even sleep without
stuffed animals to cuddle!
Ijichi-senpai!
That was a weird parting shot.
Would the stuffed animals in question
be this beat-up panda and rabbit?
That's cute.
Delete that image! Immediately!
What are you doing? We have to go after her!
Don't act like it's too much trouble!
You too, Gotoh-san!
Let's go!
R-Right!
Wait, Bocchi-chan.
Y-Yes?
What, what, what?
What, what, what?!
It's so obvious when you're sulking.
Shut up.
Senpai, are you all right?
Sorry to rush out like that.
She didn't have to be such
a jerk about it, you know?
E-Excuse me!
Bocchi-chan?
E-Excuse me...
M-Manager... said...
She said...
Bocchi-chan, breathe first!
Here, Bocchi-chan!
Th-Thank you.
Feel better?
Y-Yes.
Um... The manager told me...
Potential August Bands
• Macaroni Pencil
• Yukiguni with Tunnel
• Inoue brothers
• Ryokuoushoku Yasai
• Kessoku Band
Tell Nijika.
If she wants to perform,
she needs to audition.
I'll watch the performances
next Saturday and decide...
What?
What are you doing?
I-I'm desperately attempting
to show obedience!
You should probably go after them
before you lose them.
W-Woof!
An audition?!
Yeah!
And if we pass, she'll let us perform?
Y-Yes.
Well, why didn't she just
say so to begin with?
That sister of mine is so mean!
But that means we just have to work hard!
Isn't that nice?
Yeah, that's right.
You've got that "those two are the
biggest problem" look on your face.
Erk!
Erk
We'll record your parts in advance,
so just practice miming along!
Right!
No! No air guitars!
We've only got a week.
Don't push them so hard.
Even if they suck, the passion
will come through if they try!
We suck?
Oh, sorry!
You're really both way
better than you were.
Right, Ryo?
C'mon, back me up here!
B-Bocchi-chan?
Please don't turn into a pipe shut-in!
sorry for my momentary arrogance over my success in writing lyrics those with uncontrollable arrogance deserve a life inside a dark dank pipe.
S-Sorry for my momentary arrogance
over my success in writing lyrics.
Ah, it's The Sound of Bocchi!
Those with uncontrollable arrogance
deserve a life inside a dark, dank pipe.
So long as the rhythm section's strong,
it'll probably work out.
Y-You think?
Yeah!
I don't think they need to see us
all playing on Ryo's level.
Th-Then what do they need to see?
Hmm... enthusiasm? Growth as a band?
Growth?
Gotoh-san, thank you.
For practicing with me.
I-It's nothing...
But shouldn't we practice in a classroom
instead of this dreary place?
Oh, w-well, actually...
How am I supposed to practice with
all those judging eyes asking,
"What's a cool girl like Kita
doing with that loser?!"
Oh, I get it!
You don't want to bother people
by playing in a classroom!
You're so considerate, Gotoh-san!
She always assumes my motivations are pure!
What a nice person!
Hey, Gotoh-san...
I've been thinking about it.
I think we just need to show
that we've grown as a band—
in other words, how hard we've been working.
R-Right.
When the time comes, I want to
be able to say I gave it my all,
and that I don't have any regrets.
So please stick with me until
the day of the audition!
P-Please don't bow!
I-I'm the one who's h-happy to be here!
It's hard to know exactly
what "growth" means.
Ow!
I don't think it's quite the same
as effort put in.
My life as of late has been a whirlwind.
I started working.
I've gained the ability to occasionally
look others in the eye.
Your finger's looking better.
But I don't think that's the same thing
as growing as a band.
I've just evolved past the
water flea or euglena stage
and now stand at the starting line
of basic humanity.
I thought finally starting
the band I dreamed about
would be growth in itself, but...
I...
Sorry if I forced you to go along with this.
I mean, you kind of just got roped into
joining Kessoku Band from the start, right?
I remember you saying...
you'd been wanting
to be part of a band,
but I never actually asked you what
kind of band you wanted to be in,
or what your reasons were
for playing in this band now.
Oh, well...
Should I tell her I started because
I wanted people going crazy for me?
Everyone's got their own reasons, right?
It's not like performing live
is the only way to go now.
You can always post videos and stuff nowadays
if what you want is to get your sound out there.
See... I've got this kind of goal.
A dream, really.
So I can get a little fired up
without realizing it.
So... I worry I might have dragged you
into this against your will.
N-N-Not at all!
It's n-n-not against my will at all!
Really? That's good.
The reason you wanted a band...
It's to get famous and perform
at the Budokan, right?
My real dream is actually a little past that.
But I can't tell you just yet!
Anyway, see you tomorrow!
I spent all night thinking about my reason
for playing in this band now.
We're Kessoku Band.
We're going to play our song,
"Guitar, Solitude, and the Blue Planet"!
I do still want to become popular
and have everyone go crazy for me...
But now... it's not just for me.
It's the four of us!
A sudden evening shower falls
And yeah, it figures,
I don't have an umbrella...
Who cares how the sky's feeling, anyway?
When it's time for the seasons to change
I never figured out what
it means to have "growth."
What are you supposed to wear? Who knows?
Spring and fall... yeah, where'd they go?
But right now, what I want
is to stay with this band and
have people go crazy for us!
The pressure of information, suffocating
A spiral of vertigo
I want to make Nijika-chan's
actual dream come true.
Don't know where I am
I can hear myself breathing
so loud, so loud...
So... I can't afford to blow this audition!
But why? I can't hear the
sounds of the world...
I don't want the band to end just yet!
It's not enough, not enough,
No one knows I'm here
I screamed when I couldn't
make a scribble of a sound
Who am I supposed to show "just who I am" to?
So I'm singing just like the fool I am
Let's lay it all out to the stars!
Thank you for having us!
Pretty good.
Or so I'd like to say, but...
Drums, you're too tense.
Guitars, you're both looking down too much.
Bass, you're too holed up
in your own little world.
Still... I think I know what
kind of band you are now.
Thank you... for the feedback.
Huh? What's with that reaction?
W-Well... I mean...
I'm saying, I learned what
kind of band you are!
This is the part where you cheer.
I think she's saying you passed.
That's what I said! You passed!
Sis, you're so misleading!
Y-You mean... we did it?
We did it!
She says we passed!
Yes!
We really did it?
Ryo, did you catch it?
Gotoh-san, we did it!
Y-Yes!
It hasn't been long, but Bocchi-chan's
playing is so different.
Gotoh-san!
Yes!
You were really incredible there, Gotoh-san.
Manager.
Admit it. You liked them from the start.
C'mon, you've been keeping a window open
in the concert schedule for them.
Why tease them like that?
I wasn't teasing.
I just didn't want to put them on
until they were ready.
But while they're still
rough around the edges,
I think they've got something.
As her sister, I need to be hard on her
to make sure her band grows.
Is this what they call a sister complex?
One more word about that, and you're fired.
Right.
Okay! Let's work even harder to level up
our band in the lead-up to the concert!
Right!
Bocchi, I'm looking forward
to the new lyrics.
R-Right!
Isn't this getting exciting, Gotoh-san?!
Y-Yes!
Th-That's right! It's not over at all!
In fact, Kessoku Band's journey
is just getting started!
Now, since the ticket quota is twenty at
1,500 yen each, that means we each sell five!
Five-ticket quota...
Five-ticket quota?!
Father...
My daughter's inscribing
her name into rock history...
Mother...
I'll cook some red rice!
Sister...
You're awesome, Sis!
Dog...
Woof!
Rock! Red rice! Awesome! Woof!
Father, mother, sister, dog!
Father, mother, sister, dog.
One ticket left for...
Grandma?
B-But I doubt she'd make the three-hour trip
just to see me play...
Good.
You know Jimihen can't come, right?
Y-You think?
I s-sort of had a feeling,
but... I wasn't sure...
Futari can't go to a club like that either.
She's only five.
Aw, no fun!
It's scary in there.
STARRY NIGHT
ahoge / Kessoku Band / Macaroni Pencil / Ryokuoushoku Yasai
(all four bands) [Alphabetical Order]
8/14
open 18:00       start 18:30
adv ¥1,500       door ¥2,000
Plus 1 Drink ¥500
Mother, father.
Mother, father...
I could invite some of my friends.
My friends.
Mother?
It's not like Sis has friends of her own!
I-I might not talk about them,
but I've got lots of friends at school.
Lia—
You shouldn't say that, even as a joke.
You should grow up to have
empathy for others.
S-Sorry.
Sounds like I should talk to my friends.
Me too—
N-N-N—
N-No, that's okay!
I've got lots of friends at school.
S-See?!
You just wait for that concert!
What do I do? If I don't find buyers
for three more tickets...
Kessoku Band
I made these promotional flyers to hand out
around my neighborhood, but...
Kessoku Band
Mainly playing at clubs in the city
Four-girl rock band
I read online that stuff with a handmade feel
comes across as more charming!
But honestly...
How is someone with social anxiety
supposed to hand out flyers?
I feel so powerless.
I'm too scared to even move.
Looks like lots of my friends are coming!
Thank goodness~~~~
Looks like lots of my friends
are coming! Thank goodness!
I got 'em sold
I got 'em sold.
How are you doing, Bocchi-chan? Coming to practice today?
I want to try the new song all together!
How are you doing,
Bocchi-chan? Coming today?
I want to try the new song all together!
Th-They're all taking care of it!
Wh-What do I say back?
"I got that quota covered!"
and pretend I'm okay?
Or do I just admit,
"I can't handle the quota!"?
But if I do that...
You can't be in the band
if you can't handle your quota.
Bye-bye, Bocchi.
Senpai!
I searched through my extensive connections
and found us an amazing and
totally extroverted guitarist!
Yeah!
Rock you!
Yeah! Rock you!
Why couldn't I just accept my mom's help?!
A p-person's collapsed.
Wh-What do I do? I've got to say something...
Actually, I need an ambulance!
H-Hello?
This is the news for 4:30 pm...
W-Water... Please...
R-Right! I'll go buy some—
A-And hangover medicine.
R-Right!
And miso soup with clams...
And rice porridge too...
Preferably in a bed dressed with
freshly line-dried sheets...
Sh-She's very demanding.
For stomach upset
during a hangover
Yoi-Shaki
Clam
With the ornithine of 96 clams
Ah, right to the liver!
You're a lifesaver! Thanks so much!
I didn't think you'd really
buy me the miso soup!
I-It's nothing.
I wanna take off my head and power-wash it!
I ended up helping a very weird person.
I wanna take out my guts
and wring out all the alcohol!
W-Well, I should be going...
Say, what's your name?
H-Hitori Gotoh.
What a cute name!
Th-Thank you.
Drinking should be done
in moderation, y'know?
She said as she started drinking again!
Hair of the dog that bit ya!
So good!
Ya want some too, Hitori-chan?
Sorry it's the cheap stuff.
N-No, thanks...
Wait, you're underage, right?
Hey, you listenin'?
Yeah, she's way too weird.
Why haven't ya said anything?
I can't tell if she's
serious or playing dumb.
Hitori-chan, you're cold as ice!
Like concrete!
On the count of three, I book it!
Wh-Whaddya want?
Ya want some booze after all?
I sh-should be going...
Hey, a guitar!
Do ya play?
I'm in a band too! Indie, of course.
Sh-She plays too?!
Hey, can ya play?
I'm s-s-s-so scared!
I have to get out of here
before I say something stupid.
What's with you, Hitori-chan?
A-A-A-Actually I bought it
but gave up after one day,
so I was just heading
to a pawn shop to sell it!
Uh?
I was hoping for a far more worthy
person to use this guitar
and truly find their wings and soar,
but I d-d-don't play at all!
Sorry! Gosh, wonder how much I'll get for it!
It's all-you-can-eat yakiniku for me today!
Wait!
Giving up after one day is a waste.
You can sell it any time you want.
But if you stick with it
a little while longer,
you might become worthy
of that guitar someday.
Oh, listen to me! Tryin' to sound all wise...
Wait. Is she kind of normal after all?
Oh, I know.
How's about I give you lessons?
Oh, actually, sorry...
I lied about everything I said just now.
That's a heck of a smooth lie you told.
Wow, nice guitar!
It's clear you take good care of it.
Th-Thank you.
I play bass.
Booze and the bass are
worth more to me than my life,
so I always keep them close by.
So, uh...
Where's your bass?
Tee hee hee
I left it at the pub.
Let's go grab it, Hitori-chan!
She values her life so little...
Ta-dah! My very own bass!
Th-This is all too incomprehensible.
Super Ultra Shuton Doki EX!
I'm struggling.
Cool, huh?
Y-Yes. Very cool.
We really rocked the house
at our concert last night!
But I drank way too much at the afterparty.
Next thing I knew, the sun was up,
and I had no idea where I was!
Y-You really like drinking that much?
Sure do! Drinking lets me forget
everything, so I just...
Everything?
You know, like fears about the future.
Pension problems!
Rural depopulation! The poverty gap!
Fears about the future
Caregiving
Pension crisis
Stressful society
Low wages
Marriage
Loss of lifetime careers
Depression
Job searches
Rural
depopulation
Helplessness
Old age
Poverty gap
Unable to think of
anything but alcohol
I'm out of alcohol!
The alcohol is gone!
fidget fidget
Gotta get booze!
Life is pain
More, more!
Body builds up tolerance,
gotta drink more
Craving is temporarily
satisfied
Happiness Spiral
I call it a Happiness Spiral!
Kids, try this at home!
Um...
By the way, what were ya doing?
Explaining
Lorem ipsum, yada yada,
etc etc, blah blah blah...
Ah, I see!
Sob
I never knew you lived such a tragic life!
Sh-She's really sympathetic!
Selling tickets is so hard.
I really struggled with it at the start too!
Y-Yeah, it really is...
Okay, since you saved my life,
I'm gonna put some skin in the game.
We're gonna play a street concert, right here and now!
S-Street concert?
Yeah! You've got those flyers, after all.
The best way to sell tickets is to play
on the street and pick up an audience.
B-But...
Kessoku Band
Mainly playing at clubs in the city
Four-girl rock band
Shimo-Kitazawa STARRY
Hey, everyone!
We're about to play!
It's free, so come by if you can!
Hey, Kanazawa-Hakkei peeps!
We're about to play!
Come watch!
Wow!
I can't wait!
You're playing, girl!
Huh? You've never played outside before?
If you're that scared,
you could shut your eyes...
Or... Well, I guess you're
scared of strangers, huh?
Oh, that might just work...
I feel you.
I've been playing so long in the dark
where I can't see my fingers anyway.
Yeah. I can do it.
But just so you know...
Special Performance
Buy tickets, please!
— Kessoku Band —
1500 yen per ticket
Performing 8/14, 6PM
at Kitazawa STARRY
You're not in combat with
the people in front of you.
Don't get it twisted who your enemies are.
Enemies?
What? What's Gotoh-san like at school?
Yeah.
I think I can kind of picture it,
but... well...
Is she a loner at school, too?
Don't just say it like that!
Well, let me see...
We're in different classes, so I don't see
what she's like with her classmates, but...
It's true that I've never seen her
with another person.
Oh, she's not being bullied
or anything, though.
That's good to hear!
She's really withdrawn and people seem
to have trouble interacting with her.
It's kind of hard to know
how to approach her.
Really?
But Bocchi's so fun.
I know, right?!
Okay, we're starting!
We're playing an original song
by her band, Kessoku Band!
Let's have some applause!
Go on, play.
R-Right...
She'll stick with me for guitar practice,
but when I invite her to have lunch
with my friends, she won't come,
and she's never in her classroom...
She's...
She's ad-libbing, but she's really selling it.
Her playing is so confident.
She's giving me such a firm
foundation to play from.
Just from hearing her play,
I can tell she's having fun.
By comparison, I...
I wonder if they're all
laughing at me out there.
I'm too scared to look up.
You're doing great!
Hey, what are you doing?
Well... The guitar girl seemed nervous,
so it just came out.
Just came out?
Thank goodness~~~~
Ryo
I got 'em sold
Read by 3
How are you doing, Bocchi-chan?
Coming to practice today?
I want to try the new song all together!
Bocchi-chan...
I sure hope she's okay...
I see.
I never had any enemies here.
It was just my imagination.
She opened her eyes.
Her playing is suddenly more stable.
So this is how Hitori-chan plays.
Interesting.
That's right.
The only people here are the ones
who stopped to hear you play.
They're all smiling.
If I do more concerts,
will I see more faces like these?
Special Performance
Buy tickets, please!
— Kessoku Band —
1500 yen per ticket
Performing 8/14, 6PM
at Kitazawa STARRY
I think I'd like that.
Great work, Hitori-chan!
Th-Thank you.
Wh-What a relief...
She didn't realize I only had one eye open!
What's wrong?
Special Performance
Buy tickets, please!
— Kessoku Band —
1500 yen per ticket
Performing 8/14, 6PM
at Kitazawa STARRY
Oh, n-nothing...
Excuse me.
Y-Yes?!
Can we buy tickets to this concert?
We'll take two!
Isn't that great, Hitori-chan?
Huh? Did you freeze up from joy?
Um... That'll be 1,500 yen apiece, 3,000 total!
Right?
Y-Yes!
A-Are you sure you want
to buy those t-t-tickets?
Give it up already, Hitori-chan!
B-But I...
This was my first time watching a
street performance, but you were so good!
Keep up the good work at
your next concert, okay?
R-Right... I'll do my best.
Oh, that's right.
I got so carried away before, but I
still have one ticket left to sell...
B-But I did sell four!
Not bad for my first time!
I'll buy that last one.
The ticket.
That'll get you to your quota, right?
Y-You're sure?!
Of course. I typically operate
out of Shinjuku, so I'm close by,
and I know this club too.
Th-Thank you so much...
A concert costing over five Onikoros...
It'd better be worth it!
R-Right!
Looks like my friends can't come either.
Tickets go on sale at 5 pm
S-Same with my parents.
M-My grandma was supposed
to look after Futari,
b-but now she can't come, so...
Yeah. Makes sense...
Our audience is going to be
less than half of what we expected.
Well, it is what it is!
Let's take it in stride!
Yes, of course!
Nijika-chan always stays so cheerful,
no matter what happens.
Wow, look at that rain!
Bocchi-chan, I'm here!
M-Ma'am!
Oh, you came here for Bocchi-chan?
Heck yeah! Yay!
Y-You know each other?
She was my junior in college.
Betcher havin' an afterparty tonight, right?
Picked an izakaya yet?
You reek of booze!
I know a good one, 'kay? 'Kay?
How did you become even more
of a pain in the ass?
She's as annoying as a college student
who just learned about drinking parties.
It's just about start time, and there's
really not many people out there...
But the other bands' fans are here too,
and I'm sure they'll all listen to us!
And I'm sure more will arrive if we start.
Hey, you ever heard of this
first group? Kessoku Band?
Don't know. Don't care.
Yeah, seems like a waste of time.
W-Well, we're new,
so of course no one knows us!
Don't let it get you down!
E-Exactly!
Don't sweat it. Don't sweat it.
R-Right!
O-Okay, it's almost time!
Let's do that concert, you guys!
A pleasure to meet you!
We're Kessoku Band!
We appreciate your kind attendance
in spite of this awful weather!
Kita-chan, that's way too polite
for a rock band!
I want my mango box!
Actually, I want to disappear altogether!
Well, let's get to that first song!
Please lend your ears to our original song:
"Guitar, Solitude, and the Blue Planet"!
A sudden evening shower falls
And yeah, it figures,
I don't have an umbrella...
Who cares how the sky's feeling, anyway?
When it's time for the seasons to change
What are you supposed to wear? Who knows?
Nijika-chan's drumming feels a little slow.
Spring and fall... yeah, where'd they go?
The pressure of information, suffocating
And Kita-san's making mistakes
she didn't make in practice.
A spiral of vertigo
Ryo-san and Nijika-chan
aren't in sync at all.
Don't know where I am
I can hear myself breathing
so loud, so loud...
But why? I can't hear the
sounds of the world...
It's not enough, not enough,
No one knows I'm here
I screamed when I couldn't
make a scribble of a sound
We're not playing the way we usually do...
Who am I supposed to show "just who I am" to?
So I'm singing just like the fool I am
Let's lay it all out to the stars!
That was "Guitar, Solitude,
and the Blue Planet"!
Yeah, what a waste of time.
We should've showed up later.
Um...
Kita-chan, you need to
introduce the next song!
R-Right!
The next is another of our original songs,
and it's one we just wrote...
Our guitarist, Gotoh-san...
That band's songs sound to me
like shrill laughter all around
That band's songs are to me
like the piercing clang of a railway crossing
Don't push me forward
There's a train coming
I close my eyes
There's a halo in the darkness
I cover my ears
There's a steady beating pulse within
Deep in my chest
My heart makes my body sway
I don't want to hear anything else
Nothing but the sounds I'm making
Hey, not bad!
Yeah!
That was super cool!
That was our second song, "That Band"!
Now, here's our last song!
Kaomise
E-Excuse me... Nijika-chan?
Oh, Bocchi-chan!
I-Is something the matter?
Nah, just getting some fresh air.
I-It's been getting cold
at night lately, huh?
Sure has.
Next thing we know,
summer break's gonna be over!
I hear nothing.
I know nothing.
Summer break never ends.
I'm not a student.
Trees, water, planets, Milky Way...
Bocchi-chan! Back to reality!
S-Sorry.
E-Excuse me...
Say...
I realized something while I was
watching you play today.
You're guitarhero, aren't you?
W-Well, a-actually, n-no, about that...
It was pretty obvious from the
on-point way you were strumming.
And I finally noticed
you had the same guitar.
Um...
I am.
B-But I didn't hide it on purpose.
S-Since I'm anything but a hero right now...
I w-wanted to wait to tell you
until I fixed the way I am.
E-Especially you, Nijika-chan.
A-Are you shocked to find out?
Nah...
It made me all the more happy to have you!
What?
See, I told you I had a dream before, right?
Y-Yes?
My mom died when I was little,
and my dad was never home,
so my sister was pretty much my only family.
But since I hated being alone,
when my sis started a band,
I had her take me to her clubs all the time.
It all seemed so shining to me.
I was never happier anywhere else.
I was her inspiration for quitting her band
and starting up this club.
Starry is a place my sister made for me.
Though I'll bet she won't admit it.
So my real dream
is to make a band popular
enough for me and my sister
and make Starry even more famous!
But when I actually started my band,
I spent a while thinking that
it was kind of out of my reach.
And everyone was so disheartened today.
But every time things
are looking their worst,
Ripe Mangos
you're the one who breaks through it for us!
Bocchi-chan, you were
one heck of a hero to me today.
Ryo wants to use this band to finally
get to play music from the heart,
and Kita-chan wants to really
do something with us.
They've all invested their hopes in the band.
That reminds me, you never actually told me
what you were doing the band for now.
I...
As a guitarist, I want to make the
Kessoku Band we all care so much about
the best band it can be!
A-And I want us to become such a popular band
that we can make money
and not have to finish school...
That's a pretty tall order!
But I accept your investment!
I sure do wish you could play the way
you do in your videos every time, though...
I'll d-do my best...
But now I know it for sure!
Having you with us will
make our dreams possible!
So keep showing us more and more.
Of "Bocchi-chan's rock."
Bocchi the Rock!
Okay!